<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Database>
	<EnglishText>

		<!--Earth Kingdom-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_EARTH_KINGDOM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Earth Kingdom is one of the world's four nations. Spanning most of a continent as well as several subsidiary islands, it is the largest and most populated sovereignty in the world and encompasses much of the eastern hemisphere. The kingdom operates as a monarchy under the rule of a single Earth Monarch, although the power of its rulers has historically greatly fluctuated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_EARTH_KINGDOM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Earth Kingdom was founded after the city state of Ba Sing Se, its later capital, forcibly subjugated several other polities. As a result, the nation is traditionally characterized by significant diversity and divided into quasi-autonomous regions with their own ethnicities, cultures, governments, and laws. It is home to most earthbenders. The people of the Earth Kingdom are proud and strong; they usually adhered to a philosophy of peaceful coexistence and cooperation with the other nations of the world. Originally one of the most powerful empires in the world, the Earth Kingdom experienced a series of crises, civil wars, and political unrest in the 4th and 3rd century BG. This decline was eventually halted, and the Earth Kingdom began to flourish with a long period of internal peace and economic development during the long life of Avatar Kyoshi. However, the constitution that she helped draft was eventually undermined by Earth King Jialun, resulting in an increasingly corrupt and uncaring government as well as the growth of internal tensions. Even though, much of the Earth Kingdom continued to prosper, boasting a large economy, the country began to fall behind in regard to industrialization and technological progress.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_EARTH_KINGDOM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>TFrom the 1st century BG, the nation was increasingly targeted by the Fire Nation's imperialism, culminating in the Hundred Year War. Outpaced by its aggressive neighbor with regard to military, economy, and technology, the Earth Kingdom suffered terribly during the Great War, but long proved to be the only real obstacle that hindered the Fire Nation from achieving world domination. In 100 AG, the Earth Kingdom mostly fell to a Fire Nation-led coup, though the nation ultimately won the Hundred Year War thanks to Avatar Aang's intervention. The long process of healing followed, and the presence of several Fire Nation colonies led the Earth Kingdom to cede parts of its territory to the newly established United Republic of Nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_EARTH_KINGDOM_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>In the following decades, the Earth Kingdom exerted significant international influence and rebuilt, but also experienced a resurgence of the monarch's power. This led to a reactionary and oppressive central government that provoked growing unrest throughout the nation. In 171 AG, the Red Lotus staged an insurrection which resulted in the collapse of the government and plunged the Earth Kingdom into anarchy. The country was stabilized by Kuvira and her army, but she consequently declared an "Earth Empire" under her military dictatorship. The Earth Empire proved short-lived, ending after a failed invasion of the United Republic. Following these events, Earth King Wu decided to gradually abolish the monarchy and Earth Kingdom in favor of separate, democratic states. Despite an attempt to revive the Earth Empire during the Gaoling Crisis, the remnants of Kuvira's regime were defeated once more, with the Earth Kingdom now slowly turning into a democracy.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!--Civ Unique Unit-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_UNIT_EARTHBENDER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Earthbending, one of the four elemental bending arts, is the geokinetic ability to manipulate earth and rock in all their various forms, prevalent in the Earth Kingdom and the United Republic. Earth is the element of substance, while the people of the Earth Kingdom are diverse, strong, and enduring. Following the lion turtles' decision to relinquish their role as protectors of mankind, Oma and Shu were the first earthbenders to learn this art from the badgermoles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_UNIT_EARTHBENDER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The key to earthbending is utilizing neutral jing, which involves waiting and listening for the right moment to strike and, when that moment comes, acting decisively. In other words, earthbenders generally endure their enemies' attacks until the right opportunity to counterattack reveals itself. Famous Earthbenders include Toph Beifong, Avatar Kyoshi, Avatar Aang, and Avatar Korra.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Civ Unique Civilian-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_UNIT_CABBAGE_MERCHANT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Cai, also known as The Cabbage Merchant, was an Earth Kingdom businessman and founder of Cabbage Corp. He is most well known for exclaiming "My Cabbages!" when his cabbage cart was damaged. Originally an ordinary salesman who specialized in selling cabbages, he was constantly plagued by misfortune during his business endeavors, as his cabbages were continually destroyed or damaged after encountering Team Avatar and their enemies. Inspired by an incident at the Earthen Fire Refinery, the cabbage merchant eventually founded Cabbage Corp, a company that mainly produces automobiles and other technologies, sometime before 120 AG.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_UNIT_CABBAGE_MERCHANT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Cai excessively revered cabbages, to the degree that other people often considered his behavior odd or off-putting. He treated his vegetables with great care and wished for all those around him to also realize how great cabbages were; accordingly, he usually reacted with horror or extreme anger when someone harmed his products. For instance, he would freeze in shock[14] or demand the death sentence for those damaging his business.[11] His repeated bad luck in protecting his cabbages made Cai very paranoid, a trait he kept even after rising to lead a large company.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Civ Wonder-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_WONDER_EARTH_MONARCH_PALACE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The Earth Kingdom Royal Palace is the home of the Earth Monarch and the seat of the Earth Kingdom's government. Located within the Upper Ring at the center of Ba Sing Se, the palace and surrounding grounds served as the spiritual and political center of the entire Earth Kingdom until it fell to the Fire Nation in 100 AG and later to the Red Lotus in 171 AG. The palace is a superb example of traditional Earth Kingdom architecture and its massive scale makes it unlike anything else in the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_PAGE_WONDER_EARTH_MONARCH_PALACE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Royal Palace is almost certainly the largest palace compound in the world; with its myriad towers, gardens, shrines, courts, and plazas, it is very nearly a city in itself.[12] The palace was designed so that it was located at the figurative heart of Ba Sing Se, and by extension the Earth Kingdom. It is surrounded on all sides by the Upper Ring, home to the central government ministries and the mansions of the city's wealthiest citizens, bureaucrats, and civil servants. The palace is arranged on a north-south axis which extends beyond its walls to form the central axis of the Upper Ring.</Text>
		</Row>


	</EnglishText>
</Database>